

# Mohamed Firas Ouertani Software Engineering Student

💌 mohamedfiras.ouertani@esprit.tn 🕓 +216 53 851 047 🖪 fb.com/mohamedfirasouertani

WHO AM I: I am Mohamed Firas from Tunisia. I am a Hardworking, Skilled, Focused, Self-Motivated individual developer and a software engineer student, I spend my time working in some Web and Android projects. I also have experience in desktop applications development with JAVAFX.

## **EDUCATION**

2008-2012

Ibn-Rachik High School

Mathematics High school diploma in Mathematics

2013-Present

ESPRIT - Private Higher School Of Engineering And Technology

Software Engineering Second year of preparatory. First year of engineering

Software and Tools

**Android Studio** 

Xamarin Studio

Visual Studio

Unity 3D

**Netbeans** 

Code Blocks

Graphic

Ot

**Eclipse** 

## **EXPERIENCE**

2013-2014

**ESPRIT** 

2015

**ESPRIT** 

2016

**ESPRIT** 

2013-Present

**MFO** 

2015-Present

CyberSec

2014

**DEV-IT** 

2015-PRESENT Rantime

SDL Game Development

Developing a 2D video game programmed in C and SDL Library within a group of 5 members

Web & Desktop App. Development Developing a web application using HTML5, CSS3, PHP4 JavaScript. And developping an ERP using C++.

Web, Mobile And Desktop App. Developing E-commerce multi platform Application with: JAVA, JAVAFX, J2ME, Symfony, PHP5

Freelancer

Working in some small Web & Mobile Projects

#### STAFF Member

Cybersec is a security club in my university. As a staff member i present some workshops, also i am the creator of all challenges's Android Apps.

Internship

Helping DEV-IT Company in their Kingflex's project

Rantime Android App

I am developing a Random Chat App using Smack(Client) and Openfire(Server).

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages SQL

SQLITE ( C

C++

C# Java

Web Development

HTML5 CSS3

PHP5 JavaScript

**BDMS** 

Mysql Oracle

Integration

Gitlab, Github Frameworks

Bootstrap, Symfony

Adobe Photoshop

Oracle Database

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Flash player

Adobe After Effects

**Platforms** 

JAVAFX, J2ME

Methodology

UML, Agile (Scrum)

## **PERSONAL QUALITIES**



## **AWARD**

1st Place in ESPRIT Game Development Project 2014 My team and I win the 1st Place in SDL Game Development in my university

2nd Place in Android App Development Individual Challenge

2013

**Arabic** Native

**English** Advanced

French Advanced

German Beginner